远在光明尚未诞生之际 世界充满黑暗
Long before the birth of light, there was darkness.
在这无尽的黑暗中 孕育着黑暗精灵一族
And from that darkness came the Dark Elves.
数千年之前 族中最为残暴的精灵首领 玛勒基斯
Millennia ago, the most ruthless of their kind, Malekith
企图摧毁九界 使整个宇宙重新回到无尽的黑夜
sought to transform our universe back into one of eternal night.
因为他拥有足以毁天灭地的上古力量 以太粒子
Such evil was possible through the power of the Aether,
所以这并非痴人说梦
an ancient force of infinite destruction.
玛勒基斯
Malekith.
阿斯加德的部队来了
Asgard's forces are upon us.
我的父王博尔亲自率领高贵的阿斯加德军团
The noble armies of Asgard, led by my father, King Bor,
讨伐这群邪恶的生物
waged a mighty war against these creatures.
派献祭者出战!
Send in the Kursed!
当九界在他眼前汇聚于一线
As the Nine Worlds converged above him,
玛勒基斯终于如愿以偿释放以太
Malekith could at last unleash the Aether.
啊!
Ahh!
但是阿斯加德的军队从他手里夺下了武器
But Asgard ripped the weapon from his grasp.
黑暗精灵一族也随之倒下
Without it, the Dark Elves fell.
眼看大势已去
With the battle all but lost,
玛勒基斯孤注一掷 不惜族人性命
Malekith sacrificed his own people
丧心病狂地与阿斯加德的军队展开殊死决战
in a desperate attempt to lay waste to Asgard's army.
他们死了 我们才能活
Their deaths will mean our survival.
这场战争还远未结束
This war is far from over.
玛勒基斯战败了 以太也不复存在
Malekith was vanquished, and the Aether was no more.
或者说是我们自欺欺人地这样认为
Or so we were led to believe.
陛下 要把以太毁了吗?
Sire, the Aether. Shall we destroy it?
我也希望如此
If only we could.
但是它的力量太过强大
But its power is too great.
把它深埋地下
Bury it deep.
埋到谁都找不到的地方
Somewhere no one will ever find it.
雷神2: 黑暗世界
洛基
Loki.
你好 母后
Hello, Mother.
替我自豪吗?
Have I made you proud?
别再越弄越糟了
Please, don't make this worse.
怎么算"糟"
Define "worse".
够了!
Enough!
我要和犯人单独说话
I will speak to the prisoner alone.
我真不知道这样小题大做都是为了啥
I really don't see what all the fuss is about.
难道你还没意识到自己已犯下了滔天大罪?
Do you not truly feel the gravity of your crimes?
你所到之处 生灵涂炭 满目疮痍
Wherever you go, there is war, ruin,
血流成河
and death.
我只不过去凡间当了回他们仁慈的神
I went down to Midgard to rule the people of Earth as a benevolent god.
像您一样
Just like you.
我们不是神 我们也有生老病死
We are not gods. We are born, we live, we die.
与凡人无异
Just as humans do.
也就比他们多活5000年而已
Give or take 5,000 years.
一切都因你 洛基 觊觎王位而起
All this because Loki desires a throne.
我命中注定有争夺王位的权利
It is my birthright.
你命中注定本是死亡
Your birthright was to die
年少而亡
as a child.
你被丢弃在冰冷的岩石上
Cast out onto a frozen rock.
如果我没把你带回来
If I had not taken you in,
你连站在这恨我的机会都没有
you would not be here now to hate me.
如果我该死 那么求求你
If I am for the axe, then for mercy's sake,
快动手吧
just swing it.
我不是不喜欢和你说话
It's not that I don't love our little talks,
只是...
it's just...
我不喜欢他们
I don't love them.
要不是你的母后芙蕾嘉 你早就被处死了
Frigga is the only reason you're still alive,
而你再也不会见到她了
and you will never see her again.
你的余生都会在地牢中渡过
You will spend the rest of your days in the dungeons.
那索尔呢?
And what of Thor?
你要让那个白痴登基 却让我在枷锁里腐烂
You'll make that witless oaf king while I rot in chains.
索尔会收拾完你留下的烂摊子
Thor must strive to undo the damage you have done.
他要帮九界恢复秩序
He will bring order to the Nine Realms
然后 没错...
and then, yes...
他会登基为王
he will be king.
华纳海姆
啊!
Ah!
一切都在我的掌控之中!
I've got this completely under control!
所以到处都在着火?
Is that why everything is on fire?
啊!
Ah!
不用谢
You're welcome.
啊!
Ha!
交给你了
All yours.
你好
Hello.
我接受你的投降
I accept your surrender.
还有谁?
Anyone else?
下次咱应该从大家伙开始
Perhaps next time we should start with the big one.
快走 快!
Keep moving. Come on!
赶紧走 走前边 不准回头!
Keep moving. Go ahead of me. Don't you turn around!
接下来去哪?
Where do we go next?
霍根 九界即将重归和平
Hogun, the peace is nearly won across the Nine Realms.
你应该留在这 和你关心的人民在一起
You should stay here. Be with your people, where your heart is.
不着急回阿斯加德
Asgard can wait.
真是感激不尽
You have my thanks.
我也要感谢你
As you have mine.
海姆达尔 让我上去
Heimdall, when you're ready.
阿斯加德
华纳海姆安全了?
Is Vanaheim secure?
和诺恩海姆还有瑞亚一样安全
As are Nornheim and Ria.
要是您能亲自出马 战争肯定早结束了
Though our work would have gone more quickly with you at the fore.
你今天肯定是蜂蜜吃多了 不然嘴巴怎么这么甜
You must think I'm a piece of bread that needs to be buttered so heavily.
我说的都是实话
That was not my intent.
这是彩虹桥被摧毁以后
For the first time since Bifrost was destroyed,
九界首次重归和平
the Nine Realms are at peace.
他们会牢记我们的实力
They're well reminded of our strength
而你赢得了他们的尊重 还有我的感激
and you have earned their respect and my gratitude.
谢谢
Thank you.
一切都井然有序
Nothing out of order
除了你那悸动的心
except your confused and distracted heart.
这和简・福斯特无关 父王
This isn't about Jane Foster, Father.
凡人的生命转瞬即逝 根本不值一提
Human lives are fleeting, they're nothing.
你还是珍惜你眼前的吧
You'd be better served by what lies in front of you.
我不是以众神之父的身份给你讲这个
I'm telling you this, not as the Allfather,
而是父亲
but as your father.
你已经准备好了
You are ready.
是时候登上王位了
The time has come for you to take the throne.
尽情庆祝你的胜利吧
Embrace and celebrate what you've won.
和你的勇士们一起
Join your warriors.
喝酒吃肉 享受狂欢的喜悦
Eat and drink, revel in their celebration.
至少也得装得很享受吧
At least pretend to enjoy yourself.
再来一杯!
Another!
以前你可是要狂欢好几周的
There was a time when you would celebrate for weeks.
我还记得庆祝哈罗金之战的时候
I remember you celebrated the Battle of Harokin
你兴奋得几乎想要立刻再去下一个国家战斗
so much that you nearly started the second.
第一次凯旋确实很有趣
Well, the first was so much fun.
陪我喝一杯
Take a drink with me.
今晚众神之父肯定不会再交给你任务了
Surely, the Allfather could have no further task for you tonight.
不 这是我自己的任务
No, this is one I set myself.
你每晚都消失 真让人想不注意都难
It does not go unnoticed that you disappear each night.
一共有九个国度
There are nine realms.
未来阿斯加德的国王不能只关注一个
The future king of Asgard must focus on more than one.
感谢你的英勇和你的忠告
I thank you for your sword
亲爱的席芙小姐
and for your counsel, good Lady Sif.
伦敦
嗨
Hi.
给我讲讲你的故事?
So, what's the story with you?
为什么要有个故事? 没什么故事
Why does there have to be a story? There's no story.
我们约会的前十分钟你都把头埋在
You spent the first ten minutes of our date
只有三个选择的菜单里
hiding behind a menu that has three choices on it.
鸡肉 蔬菜和鱼 简
It's either chicken, vegetarian, or fish, Jane.
我猜肯定有个故事
I think there's a story
而且故事里应该有个男人
and I'm thinking the story involves a guy.
这很复杂
It's complicated.
他还在你身边?
Is he still around?
不 他...
No, he...
他离开了
went away.
我也经历过
I've been there.
分别很痛苦 对吧?
The going away. It's hard, isn't it?
我以前的女朋友
I was seeing a woman
她去纽约工作了
and she took a job in New York.
后来 爱情熬不过距离
Eventually, the distance killed it.
后来才知道她不停地和别的男人上床
And the fact that she kept sleeping with other dudes.
- 不是吧!  - 多了去了
- No!  - Oh, so many.
给我们来点红酒可以吗?
Hi. Could we get some wine, please?
当然 我也想喝
Sure, I'd love some.
理查德 这是黛西
Richard, this is Darcy.
你来这干嘛?
What are you doing here?
啊 欢迎
Oh. Hello.
我去实验室干活 又去了你妈家
So, I show up to work at the lab/your mom's house,
满心期待你穿着睡衣到处乱逛
fully expecting you to be moping around in your pajamas,
吃着冰激凌犯着某人的花痴...
eating ice cream and obsessing about...
你知道我指的是谁
you know who.
好吧
Ah.
但你没有 你穿着漂亮的衣服
But you're not. You're wearing lady clothes.
居然还洗了澡是吧? 挺好闻的
You even showered, didn't you? You smell good.
你说这些有什么意义吗?
Is there a point to all this?
最好有点意义
Because there really needs to be a point to all this.
好的
Right.
还记得那些你丢在一旁再没看过的仪器吧?
You know all that scientific equipment you don't look at anymore?
你可能想看看这个
You might want to start looking at it again.
这就是我们为什么大老远来这
This is the reason we came all the way out here.
坏了吧
It's malfunctioning.
我当时也这么说的
That's what I said.
我当时也这么做的
That's what I did.
我还以为你有更科学点的招呢
I thought you would do something a little more scientific.
- 没事的  - 是啊 这...
- I'm sure it's nothing.  - Yeah, it's...
看起来可不像没事
It doesn't look like nothing.
上边的读数好像是艾瑞克经常提到的
It kind of looks like the readings that Erik was rambling about.
艾瑞克是我们的朋友
Our friend Erik
有点脑残
kind of went banana balls.
他对这个没兴趣
He's not interested.
- 我也没兴趣  - 我挺有兴趣的
- I'm not interested.  - I'm interested.
你该走了
It's time for you to go now.
好吧
Okay.
简单明了 还挺可爱
Short but sweet.
她得看看病了
She needs help.
我准备点海鲈鱼
I think I'm going to have the sea bass.
海鲈鱼 海鲈鱼不错
Sea bass, yeah. Sea bass is good.
海鲈鱼 海鲈鱼 海鲈鱼
Sea bass, sea bass, sea bass, sea bass, sea bass, sea bass.
海鲈鱼...
Sea bass...
海鲈鱼
Sea bass.
简?
Jane?
别再说"海鲈鱼"了
Maybe you should stop saying "sea bass"
你还是去找你朋友吧
and go after your friend.
和你在一起很有趣
This was so fun.
我自己坐着念"海鲈鱼"好了
I'll just stay here and say "sea bass" alone.
我恨你
And I hate you.
为啥? 我说他挺可爱的
What? I said he was cute.
闭上嘴开车
Just shut up and drive.
下个路口左转
You need to take the next left.
- 这是谁?  - 我带的实习生
- Who's he?  - He's my intern.
- 你还带实习生?  - 是啊
- You have an intern?  - Oh, yeah.
你好 福斯特博士
Hello, Dr. Foster.
跟你合作很荣幸
It's such a great honor to be working with you.
好了 我要给艾瑞克打电话
Right. I have to call Erik.
哦 向右转
Oh, take a right.
再向左转
And a left.
我已经完全掌握如何在伦敦开车了
I have totally mastered driving in London.
嗨 艾瑞克 还是我 你在哪?
Hi, Erik. It's me again. Where are you?
你说你在这有新发现 所以我就来了 然后你就消失了
I came here because you said you were onto something, and then you vanish.
我现在就在巨石阵现场
I'm here at Stonehenge
来看看今天发生了什么趣事
for what has been an interesting unfolding of events today.
警方已于今天早晨十一点后不久
The police were called to the scene
到达我所在的现场
shortly after 11 A.M. this morning
一位看似正常的游客步入这片区域之后
after a seemingly harmless rambler approached the area.
突然脱掉衣服 赤身裸体
Then, decided to strip naked and effectively
并不时地用科学装置来吓唬其他游客
terrorize tourists there with scientific equipment.
同时宣称他正在拯救他们
Whilst shouting that he was trying to save them.
之后 此人被辨认出是天文物理学家艾瑞克・赛尔维格博士
The man, later identified as noted astrophysicist Dr. Erik Selvig
现已被警方带走问话
has been called in for questioning by police.
拜托 这很有意思
Come on, this is exciting.
看! 这个实习生也感兴趣
Look! The intern is excited.
我叫"伊安"
"Ian."
想要相位计吗?
Do you want the phase meter?
- 不想  - 把相位计带上
- No.  - Bring the phase meter.
就是那个看起来像个烤面包机的东西
The toaster-looking thing.
是 我知道相位计长啥样
Yeah. I know what the phase meter is.
我该怎么换掉这个铃声啊?
How do I change the ring-tone on this thing?
作为拥有三个学位的天体物理学家
An astrophysicist with three degrees
换个铃声应该小菜一碟吧
should be able to change her own ring-tone.
你为什么要给我打电话?
Why are you calling me?
我不想用喊的方式告诉你 实习生说走这边
I didn't want to shout. Intern says it's this way.
- 是"伊安" 我叫伊安  - 嘘
- "Ian." My name is Ian.  - Shh.
我是不会为科学献身的
I am not getting stabbed in the name of science.
没事 我们是美国人
It's okay, we're Americans.
那样就能使他们喜欢我们吗?
Is that supposed to make them like us?
- 他们会走开的  - 嘘
- They'll make it go away.  - Shh.
哦 是小孩
Oh, they're kids.
你们是警察吗?
Are you the police?
不是 我们是科学家 错 只有我是科学家
No, we're scientists. Well, I am.
谢了
Thanks.
我们刚刚发现的
We just found it.
能带我们去看看吗?
Can you show us?
看起来不对啊
That doesn't seem right.
它去哪了?
Where'd it go?
太...
That's...
太难以置信了!
That's incredible!
什么情况?
What happened?
有时候他们会回来
Sometimes they come back.
有时候回不来
Sometimes they don't.
我也想扔点东西!
I want to throw something!
简 把你的鞋给我
Jane, give me your shoe.
我没见过有这种显示自从...
I haven't seen readings like this since...
自从...
Since...
上次在新墨西哥州?
New Mexico?
什么也别碰!
Don't touch anything!
把你的鞋给我
Give me your shoe.
哦
Oh.
你刚扔的是车钥匙吗?
Were those the car keys?
哇 啊!
Whoa. Ah!
哦!
Oh!
黛西!
Darcy!
哦!
Oh!
是以太粒子唤醒了我们
The Aether awakens us.
又到了"天体汇聚"的时刻
The Convergence returns.
你迟到了
You're late.
欢愉有时候比战争压力更大
Merriment can sometimes be a heavier burden than battle.
那其中之一肯定出了问题
Then you're doing one of them incorrectly.
也许是吧
Perhaps.
星星离这有多远?
How fare the stars?
还依旧闪烁
Still shining.
从这里 我能看到九个国度和十万亿的灵魂
From here, I can see nine realms and ten trillion souls.
能想起来我教你有关"天体汇聚"的事吗?
Do you recall what I taught you of the Convergence?
可以
Yes.
九星连珠
The alignment of the worlds.
又要到了 是吗?
It approaches, doesn't it?
从我的时钟开始走之后 整个宇宙再也看不到这个奇迹了
The universe hasn't seen this marvel since before my watch began.
少数人能感觉到它 更极个别的人能看见它
Few can sense it. Even fewer can see it.
但它的影响却是具有危险性的
But while its effects can be dangerous,
真心好美
it is truly beautiful.
我什么也看不见
I see nothing.
也许这不是你所寻找的美
Or, perhaps, that is not the beauty you seek.
她怎么样了?
How is she?
你的人类姑娘 她很聪明
She's quite clever, your mortal.
她现在还没弄明白
She doesn't know it yet,
但她也在研究"天体汇聚"
but she studies the Convergence as well.
甚至...
Even...
什么?
What?
我看不见她了
I can't see her.
简!
Jane!
你到底去哪了?
Where the hell were you?
你没叫警察吧
Tell me you didn't call the police.
那我该怎么做?
What was I supposed to do?
- 别叫警察  - 我都快吓死了
- Not call the police.  - I was freaking out.
你叫警察 他们就会叫联邦调查员
You call the cops, they call the Feds.
下一步你是知道的 神盾局的人会把这地方包围的
Next thing you know, we have S.H.I.E.L.D. crawling all over
- 这就是下一个"51区"  - 简
- "Area 51-ing" the place.  - Jane.
51区 美国位于内华达州的秘密军事基地 外人禁止入内
我们有稳定的重力异常
We had a stable gravitation anomaly.
而且畅通无阻
We had unimpeded access.
我们仅有的竞争对手才十岁!
Our only competition was ten years old!
简! 你消失五个小时了
Jane! You were gone for five hours.
什么?
What?
好奇怪啊
That's weird.
重色轻友
Typical.
简
Jane.
抱歉 我只是想确定一下你是真的
Sorry. I just needed to make sure you were real.
今天好奇怪
It's been a very strange day.
我是 简 什么...
I am. Jane, what...
你死哪去了?
Where were you?
你到哪去了?
海姆达尔看不到你
Heimdall cannot see you.
我就在你离开我的地方
I was right here where you left me.
我一直等你 经常想你想得泪流满面
I was waiting, and then I was crying
然后我还四处去找你
and then I went out looking for you.
你说你会回来的
You said you were coming back.
我知道 我知道 但彩虹桥被毁坏了
I know. I know, but the Bifrost was destroyed.
九界都陷入了混乱
The Nine Realms erupted into chaos.
战乱四起 盗贼横行
Wars were raging, marauders were pillaging.
我必须结束这些杀戮
I had to put an end to the slaughter.
借口编得还不赖
As excuses go, it's not terrible.
但我在电视上见你了 你在纽约!
But I saw you on TV. You were in New York!
简 我浴血奋战 都是为了保护你
Jane, I fought to protect you from the dangers of my world
但我错了
but I was wrong.
我是个傻瓜
I was a fool.
但我相信是命运又让你我相聚
But I believe that fate brought us together.
简 我不知道你在哪 发生了什么 但我知道...
Jane, I don't know where you were, or what happened, but I do know this...
什么?
What?
我知道...
I know...
你真的知道吗?
You do?
知道什么?
Do what?
什么?
What?
嘿!
Hey!
这是你干的吗?
Is this you?
我们正忙着呢
Uh, we're kind of in the middle of something here.
我十分肯定我们要进局子了
Um, I'm pretty sure we are getting arrested.
咱们待会再说
Hold that thought.
看看你 还是这么有型
Look at you, still all muscly and everything.
你们那怎么样了?
How's space?
还行吧
Space is fine.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
- 你是简・福斯特?  - 是的
- Are you Jane Foster?  - Yes.
你认识这个人吗?
Do you know this man?
他是我的实习生
He's my intern.
我实习生的实习生
My intern's intern.
你非法闯入私人领地了 你们都是
This is private property and you're trespassing, the lot of you.
你们得和我走一趟
You'll have to come with me.
简
Jane.
- 简  - 索尔?
- Jane.  - Thor?
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
发生了什么?
What just happened?
把手放在头上 退后
Place your hands on your heads. Step back.
这位女士生病了
This woman is unwell.
她很危险
She's dangerous.
我也是
So am I.
呼叫武装警力到现场
Requesting armed response officers to scene.
- 抱紧我  - 你要干什么?
- Hold on to me.  - What are you doing?
我勒个去
Holy shit.
我还想再来一次
We have to do that again.
嗨
Hi.
欢迎来到阿斯加德
Welcome to Asgard.
斯瓦塔尔海姆
看看我还剩下什么 阿拉冈
Look upon my legacy, Algrim.
我都快想不起来世界一片黑暗的感觉了
I can barely remember a time before the light.
我们的幸存将会是您最大的财富
Our survival will be your legacy.
阿斯加德一族让我们受得罪 总有一天我会让他们加倍奉还
The Asgardians will suffer as we have suffered.
我要找回以太
I will reclaim the Aether.
我将重建我们的世界
I will restore our world.
终结这个堕落的宇宙
And I will put an end to this poisoned universe.
这是什么?
What's that?
别动
Be still.
这不是地球上的物质 会是什么呢?
This is not of Earth. What is it?
我们还不知道
We do not know.
但由于体内有巨大的能量相互冲撞 她挺不了多久的
But she will not survive the amount of energy surging within her.
那不是量子发电机吗?
That's a quantum field generator, isn't it?
这是灵魂锻造机
It's a soul forge.
灵魂锻造机能把分子能量从一个地方转变到另一个地方吗?
Does a soul forge transfer molecular energy from one place to another?
可以
Yes.
那就是量子发电机
Quantum field generator.
你拿我说过的话当放屁吗?
My words are mere noises to you that you ignore them completely?
她生病着呢
She is ill.
她是个凡人
She is mortal.
疾病是她应有的体征
Illness is their defining trait.
我把她带到这来 因为我们能帮助她
I brought her here because we can help her.
她不属于阿斯加德
She does not belong here in Asgard
就如山羊逃不过被送上餐桌的命运
any more than a goat belongs at a banquet table.
他刚说啥...
Did he just...
你以为你是谁?
Who do you think you are?
我是奥丁 阿斯加德的国王
I am Odin, King of Asgard.
九界的保护者
Protector of the Nine Realms.
哦 呃 我...
Oh. Well, I'm...
我知道你是谁 简・福斯特
I know very well who you are, Jane Foster.
你给你爸提过我了?
You told your dad about me?
她体内有某种东西 父王
Something is within her, Father.
是我从没见过的物质
Something I have not seen before.
在她的世界也有治疗者
Her world has its healers.
他们叫"医生" 让他们去解决吧
They are called "doctors." Let them deal with it.
守卫 把她带回凡间
Guards, take her back to Midgard.
别动 我建议...
No, I would not...
最好别碰她
touch her.
简 你还好吗?
Jane, are you all right?
嗯
Yeah.
这不可能啊
It's impossible.
是她感染的物质... 在保护她
The infection... It's defending her.
不是
No.
它是在保护它自己
It's defending itself.
跟我来
Come with me.
有些物质在宇宙形成之前就存在了
There are relics that pre-date the universe itself.
她体内的物质应该就是其中之一
What lies within her appears to be one of them.
九界并非一直存在的
The Nine Realms are not eternal.
他们曾迎来黑暗后的黎明
They had a dawn
也必将经历辉煌后的黄昏
as they will have a dusk.
但在黎明之前
But before that dawn
黑暗势力 或者说黑暗精灵 一直对宇宙占有着绝对的统治权
the dark forces, the Dark Elves, reigned absolute and unchallenged.
"在无尽的黑暗中诞生的黑暗精灵
"Born of eternal night
会偷走宇宙的光明"
the Dark Elves come to steal away the light."
在我还是孩子的时候 母后就给我们讲过这些故事
I know these stories. Mother told them to us as children.
他们的首领玛勒基斯用黑暗制造了一个武器
Their leader Malekith made a weapon out of that darkness
被称为以太粒子
and it was called the Aether.
其它神物基本都是石头状的
While the other relics often appear as stones
只有以太是多变的液体
the Aether is fluid and everchanging.
它能将任何物体变为黑暗物质
It changes matter into dark matter.
它会寻找寄主 吸取寄主的生命力
It seeks out host bodies, drawing strength from their life-force.
玛勒基斯想要利用以太的能量
Malekith sought to use the Aether's power
让黑暗重新统治宇宙
to return the universe to one of darkness.
但是在经历了漫长的浴血奋战之后
But, after eternities of bloodshed
我的父王博尔最终获胜
my father Bor finally triumphed
迎来了数千年的和平时代
ushering in a peace that lasted thousands of years.
他是怎样获胜的?
What happened?
他把他们都消灭了
He killed them all.
你确定都消灭了吗?
Are you certain?
传言说以太也和他们一起被消灭了
The Aether was said to have been destroyed with them,
但如今却又出现了
and yet here it is.
黑暗精灵已经死了
The Dark Elves are dead.
你的书上有顺便提到怎么把它从我身上弄出来吗?
Does your book happen to mention how to get it out of me?
没有
No.
没有提到
It does not.
九界即将连成一线
The worlds are nearly aligned.
你将成为最后一个"献祭者"
You will be the last of the cursed.
我愿意牺牲自己
Let my life be sacrificed.
就如同我们的人民曾做出的牺牲
It is no less than our people did.
还有你所做的牺牲一样
Or you have done.
你将成为黑暗的使者
You will become darkness.
你会一直维持这个状态直到生命消耗殆尽
Cursed to this existence until it consumes you.
在那之前 我们的敌人都不是你的对手
Until then. no power our enemies possess can stop you.
我会彻底击垮他们的防御 助你重建黑暗的宇宙
I will tear down their defenses and ensure your return to a universe reborn.
让我们看管这些无赖真是大材小用了
Acting as caretakers to these scoundrels is beneath us.
哦 拜托! 如果他们在你身下
Oh, please! If they were beneath you,
我的大个子朋友 他们肯定活不了
my rotund friend, they'd all be dead.
- 保持队形!  - 快走!
- Keep in line!  - Move it!
奥丁总是给我送来新朋友啊
Odin continues to bring me new friends.
真是考虑周到
How thoughtful.
我送来的那些书 没有你喜欢的吗?
The books I sent, do they not interest you?
我就要这样度过余生吗? 光读书就行了?
Is that how I am to while away eternity? Reading?
我已经尽全力让你过得舒适了 洛基
I've done everything in my power to make you comfortable, Loki.
是吗?
Have you?
奥丁也这么关心我吗?
Does Odin share your concern?
索尔呢?
Does Thor?
他们如此记挂我一定很累吧
It must be so inconvenient, them asking after me day and night.
你心里清楚 走到这一步完全是你咎由自取
You know full well it was your actions that brought you here.
我咎由自取?
My actions?
我只不过是将你们一直骗我的谎言变成了事实而已...
I was merely giving truth to the lie that I had been fed my entire life...
我生来就该是国王
That I was born to be a king.
国王?
A king?
一个真正的国王敢于承认自己的错误
A true king admits his faults.
而你怎么解释自己在地球上大开杀戒的事实?
What of the lives you took on Earth?
和奥丁杀过的人数相比
A mere handful compared to the number
我的根本不值一提
that Odin has taken himself.
- 你父亲...  - 他不是我父亲!
- Your father...  - He's not my father!
那我也不是你的母亲吗?
Then am I not your mother?
不是
You're not.
你总是能看透别人 但就是看不透自己
You're always so perceptive about everyone but yourself.
你来找我的时候就知道我有麻烦了吗?
When you came for me, you knew I was in trouble.
当海姆达尔看不到你时
Heimdall had lost sight of you.
就说明你已经不在地球上了
You were no longer on Earth.
怎么可能?
How is that possible?
我想你当时处于交界的位置
I believe you were and you weren't.
九界在宇宙之树中穿梭
The Nine Realms travel within Yggdrasil
环绕着人类的国度旋转 就像你们地球围着太阳转一样
orbiting Midgard much the way your planets orbit the sun.
每隔5000年 九界的旋转位置会连成一线
And every 5,000 years, the worlds align perfectly
我们把这个现象叫做"天体汇聚"
and we call this the Convergence.
在这段时间 九界的边界就会变得模糊
During this time, the borders between worlds become blurred.
你很有可能是找到了其中一个模糊界限
It's possible you found one of these points.
边界没有关闭已经很幸运了
We are lucky that it remained open.
一旦九界偏离了汇聚的直线
Once the worlds pass out of alignment
连接点就会消失
then the connection is lost.
我喜欢你解释的方式
I like the way you explain things.
我会怎样?
What's going to happen to me?
我会找到办法救你的 简
I'll find a way to save you, Jane.
- 可是你父王说...  - 我父王也不是无所不知的
- Your father said there was...  - My father doesn't know everything.
这话可别让他听见
Don't let him hear you say that.
简・福斯特...
Jane Foster...
这位是芙蕾嘉
Please meet Frigga,
阿斯加德的王后 也是我的母亲
Queen of Asgard, and my mother.
您好
Hi.
快走!
Move!
去地牢!
To the dungeons!
快点!
Come on!
你应该走左边的楼梯
You might want to take the stairs to the left.
是地牢
The prisons.
- 洛基...  - 去吧
- Loki... - Go.
我会保护她的
I will look after her.
怎么感觉他们很讨厌被囚禁一样!
It's as if they resent being imprisoned!
这些混蛋就是生在福中不知福
There's no pleasing some creatures.
回到你们自己的牢房里去 概不追责
Return to your cells, no further harm will come to you.
我保证
You have my word.
好极了 我收回对你的承诺
Very well, you do not have my word.
派一队人去武器库
Send a squadron to the weapons vault.
不惜一切 守住地牢
Defend it at all costs. Secure the dungeon.
- 奥丁  - 芙蕾嘉
- Odin. - Frigga.
去啊!
Go!
只是小事一桩
It's a skirmish.
不要担心
Nothing to fear.
你从来不擅长撒谎
You've never been a very good liar.
带她去你的房间吧
Take her to your chambers.
骚乱平息后我去找你们
I'll come for you when it's safe.
你要小心
You take care.
经历了那么多大风大浪
Despite all I have survived,
我的王后还是这么担心我
my queen still worries over me.
没有我的担心
It's only because I worry over you
你可走不过那些大风大浪
that you have survived.
听清我的话
Listen to me now.
你需要完全照我的话做 不要有任何疑问
I need you to do everything I ask, no questions.
好的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
阿斯加德的宫殿被摧毁了! 去保护国王!
The throne of Asgard is destroyed! To the king!
芙蕾嘉有危险
Frigga.
退下吧 怪物
Stand down, creature,
否则我就不客气了
and you may still survive this.
我可没那么好吓唬 女士
I have survived worse, woman.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是玛勒基斯
I am Malekith.
我要取回我的东西
And I would have what is mine.
你拿走了一样东西 孩子
You have taken something, child.
还回来吧
Give it back.
女巫!
Witch!
以太在哪里?
Where is the Aether?
我永远不会告诉你
I'll never tell you.
这话我信
I believe you.
不!
No!
宇宙每5000年是一个循环
The universe rotates on a 5,000 year cycle
每个循环都会有一次九球连珠的现象
and once a cycle, all the worlds align.
假设... 假设这是我们的星球
Imagine... imagine that this is our world.
哦 谢谢 这是其它星球
Oh, thank you. And this is another world.
正常情况下 他们是错开的
Normally, they're separate.
但是在汇聚的时候
But during the Alignment,
九界彼此都是相连的
everything is connected, all nine realms.
九界之间可以互相穿梭
All nine realms are passing through each other
不管是重力 还是光 甚至是物质
and gravity, light, and even matter,
都可以从一个世界进入另一个世界
is crashing from one world to the other.
但是如果这一切发生在现在 后果将不堪设想
But if this happens to us now, the result will be cataclysmic.
我的重力峰值仪可以稳定天体汇聚的焦点
My gravimetric spikes can stabilize the focal point of the Convergence.
这样一来 汇聚的直线
This time, the Alignment
和其他星球就会和我们错开
and all the other worlds would just pass us by.
太棒了简直
It's beautiful.
非常简单 还有疑问吗?
It's simple. Any questions?
有
Yeah.
能把鞋还我吗?
Can I have my shoe back?
好好养伤吧 你需要力量去收回以太
Heal. You will need your strength to reclaim the Aether.
当你苏醒后 我们将彻底消灭他们
And when you wake, we will kill them all.
简・福斯特?
Jane Foster?
请跟我们来
You need to come with us.
我们现在还无法恢复宫殿的保护屏障
We are still unable to restore the palace shields.
我们的大炮探测不到他们
Our artillery cannot detect them.
甚至连海姆达尔都看不到他们
Even Heimdall cannot see them.
陛下 我们彻底失去防御力了
My king, we are all but defenseless.
你把她囚禁起来了?
She's your prisoner now?
都退下吧
Leave us.
我不想和你争辩
I do not wish to fight with you.
我也不想争
Nor I with you.
但我想去追查玛勒基斯
But I intend to pursue Malekith.
以太现在在我们手上
We possess the Aether.
玛勒基斯会来找我们的
Malekith will come to us.
没错 然后他会彻底摧毁我们
Yes, and he will destroy us.
你高估了那些怪物
You overestimate the power of these creatures.
不 我更重视我们人民的生命
No, I value our people's lives.
我会带简去黑暗世界 然后把敌人赶出阿斯加德
I'll take Jane to the Dark World, and draw the enemy away from Asgard.
当玛勒基斯将以太从简身上取出时
When Malekith pulls the Aether from Jane,
它就会暴露在外面 脆弱不堪
it will be exposed and vulnerable.
我会一举歼灭他们
And I will destroy it and him.
一旦你失败了 这个武器就会
If you fail, you risk this weapon
落入敌人手中 这太危险
falling into the hands of our enemies.
坐以待毙的风险更大
The risk is far greater if we do nothing.
说不定他的飞船已经在我们头顶
His ship could be over our heads right now,
我们却还一无所知
we would never even know it.
即便他有胆入侵
If and when he comes
他的军队倒在一万阿斯加德精兵手下
his men will fall on 10,000 Asgardian blades.
又会有多少人死在他们手里呢?
And how many of our men shall fall on theirs?
我不在乎!
As many as are needed!
啊!
Ah!
我们要战斗!
We will fight!
直到最后一个人倒下
Till the last Asgardian breath.
直到最后一滴血流尽
Till the last drop of Asgardian blood.
那你和玛勒基斯又有什么区别?
Then how are you different from Malekith?
我的儿子 区别就在于我会赢
The difference, my son, is that I will win.
简不回我电话 艾瑞克也不回我电话
Jane isn't calling me back, Erik isn't calling me back,
连白痴的神盾局也不回我电话
stupid S.H.I.E.L.D. isn't calling me back.
- 神盾局是什么?  - 这是秘密
- What's S.H.I.E.L.D?  - It's a secret.
嘿 艾瑞克 我是黛西
Hey, Erik, it's Darcy again.
索尔回来了 他把简带去了阿斯加德
Thor came back, he took Jane to Asgard,
我现在有点不知所措
and I'm not sure what I'm supposed to do.
本周还有以下新闻
Something else went missing this week
曾因卷入外星人入侵事件而闻名的
when astrophysicist Dr. Erik Selvig
天体物理学博士艾瑞克・赛尔维格
notable for his involvement in the alien invasion of New York
赤身裸体穿过...
streaked nude across...
黛西 你得来看看这个
Darcy, you really need to look at this.
你朋友艾瑞克...
Your friend, Erik...
他姓啥来着?
What was his last name again?
接着朝古迹内的游客大声喊叫
And began shouting at visitors to the historic site.
随后他被警方关押看守
He was later taken into police custody
以便于进行精神测评
for psychiatric evaluation.
目前警方仍拒绝确认...
Police are still refusing to confirm...
你没来参加奥丁的军事会议
You were not at Odin's war council.
你父亲已下令关闭彩虹桥
The Bifrost is closed by your father's orders.
无人能进
No one is to come
也无人能出
or to go.
我们面对的敌人连我也无法看见
We face an enemy that is invisible even to me.
这样的门卫还有什么用?
What use is a guardian such as that?
玛勒基斯不会罢休 这你也明白
Malekith will return, you know this.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我不能违逆国王的旨意 即便是为了你
I cannot overrule my king's wishes. Not even for you.
我不是那个意思
I'm not asking you to.
九界需要一个强大 无人敢挡的众神之父
The realms need their Allfather strong and unchallenged
无论他是否真是如此
whether he is or not.
但他不再明智了 海姆达尔
But he is blinded, Heimdall
被仇恨与悲伤蒙蔽
by hatred and by grief.
我们都一样
As are we all.
我还足够清醒
I see clearly enough.
风险太大了
The risks are too great.
往后的每一件事都毫无定数
Everything we do from here on is a risk.
我们别无选择
There is no other way.
你需要我做什么?
What do you require of me?
我请求你违抗国王的命令
What I'm about to ask of you is treason of the highest order.
成功了会被流放 失败则死路一条
Success will bring us exile and failure shall mean our death.
玛勒基斯知道以太就在这里 他能感受到它的力量
Malekith knew the Aether was here. He can sense its power.
我们再不行动 他就会卷土重来
If we do nothing, he will come for it again
但这一次 阿斯加德只会覆灭
but this time, lay waste to all of Asgard.
我们必须把简转移出去
We must move Jane off-world.
彩虹桥已经关闭
The Bifrost has been shut down
宇宙魔方被锁在宝库内
and the Tesseract locked away in the vault.
离开阿斯加德还有途径 只是鲜为人知
There are other paths off Asgard. Ways known only to a few.
确切的说 只有一个人
One, actually.
不行
No.
索尔 过了这么久
Thor. After all this time
你总算是来看我了
and now you come to visit me.
为什么?
Why?
是来幸灾乐祸? 还是讥讽嘲弄?
Have you come to gloat? To mock?
洛基 够了
Loki, enough.
别再用幻象骗我
No more illusions.
现在你看见我了 哥哥
Now you see me, brother.
她死前痛苦吗?
Did she suffer?
我不是来与你分享痛苦的
I did not come here to share our grief.
我想为你提供一个弥补的机会
Instead I offer you the chance of a far richer sacrament.
继续
Go on.
我知道你和我一样渴望复仇
I know you seek vengeance as much as I do.
你帮我逃出阿斯加德 我就给你机会
You help me escape Asgard and I will grant it to you.
复仇的机会
Vengeance
然后 再回到这里
and afterward, this cell.
你一定是走投无路了 才会来找我帮忙
You must be truly desperate to come to me for help.
你凭什么相信我?
What makes you think you can trust me?
我不信
I don't.
母亲相信
Mother did.
但在过去那么多次兵戎相见中
But you should know that when we fought each other in the past,
我确实隐隐地希望着
I did so with a glimmer of hope
我的弟弟仍然和曾经一样
that my brother was still in there somewhere.
这种希望再不会有了
That hope no longer exists to protect you.
你若背叛我 我就杀了你
You betray me, and I will kill you.
唔
Hmm.
我们什么时候开始?
When do we start?
他一定会背叛你
He will betray you.
让他试试看
He will try.
这可不像你啊 哥哥
This is so unlike you, brother.
偷偷摸摸的
So clandestine.
你确定不打算直接砸开一条路?
Are you sure you wouldn't rather just punch your way out?
你再烦 我就真的砸了
If you keep speaking, I just might.
行 都听你的
Fine. As you wish.
当我不存在
I'm not even here.
这样是不是好点了?
Is this better?
至少比刚才好多了
It's better company at least.
其实还可以更不显眼些
Still, we could be less conspicuous.
唔 哥哥 你真是迷人
Mmm, brother, you look ravishing.
就算这样我也能轻松干掉你
It will hurt no less when I kill you in this form.
很好 或者你更喜欢我变成你的新朋友
Very well. Perhaps you prefer one of your new companions
你似乎很喜欢他们
given that you seem to like them so much.
哦 这样好多了
Oh, this is much better.
噢
Ooh.
制服有些太紧了
The costume is a bit much. So tight.
但这种自信的感觉...
But the confidence...
我能感到正义的力量扑面而来
I can feel the righteousness surging.
嘿 你想来场关于真相的激动人心的讨论吗?
Hey, do you want to have a rousing discussion about truth?
或者荣耀? 还是爱国主义?
Honor? Patriotism?
上帝保佑美...
God bless Amer...
干嘛?
What?
你至少给我一把武器吧
You could at least furnish me with a weapon.
我的匕首 或者随便什么
My dagger, something.
这才对
At last.
总算有点常识
A little common sense.
你不是喜欢恶作剧吗
And I thought you liked tricks.
然后呢? 你心爱的凡人正被英灵战士重重守卫
Well, what then? Your lovely mortal is being guarded by a legion of Einherjar
你接近半米都会被发现
who will see you coming from miles away.
去救她的不能是我
I won't be the one who comes for her.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
这是怎么...
What the...
很好 那就走吧
Good. Let's go.
你是...
You're...
我是洛基 你或许听说过我
I'm Loki, you may have heard of me.
这一下是为了纽约
That was for New York.
我喜欢她
I like her.
众神之父呢?
And what of the Allfather?
向他通告一切叛国罪行是我誓约的责任
It is my sworn duty to notify him of crimes against the throne.
你紧急召唤我来
You called me here on an urgent matter.
出了什么事?
What is it?
有人叛国 大人
Treason, my lord.
是谁?
Whose?
我
Mine.
陛下!
My king!
那个凡人被带走了
The mortal has been taken.
阻止索尔
Stop Thor.
不惜任何手段
By any means necessary.
他们在那儿! 抓住他们
There they are! Take them.
听我命令
On my command.
我拖住他们 你带她走
I'll hold them off. Take her.
谢谢
Thank you.
敢背叛他 我就杀了你
Betray him, and I'll kill you.
我也很高兴见到你 席芙
It's good to see you, too, Sif.
即便你能得到洛基的帮助 解救这位凡人
Assuming you can get Loki's help and you can free this mortal
又有什么用呢?
what good would it do?
我们一走出宫殿就死定了
We'd all be dead the minute we step one foot outside the palace.
这就是为什么我们不能用走的
That, my friend, is why we won't be leaving by foot.
我会尽量为你争取时间
I will give you as much time as I can.
谢谢你 我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
敢背叛他 哪怕只是想想...
If you even think about betraying him...
你就会杀了我?
You'll kill me?
显然 你得排队才行
Evidently, there will be a line.
我以为你说过你会开这东西
I thought you said you knew how to fly this thing.
我说的是 "能有多难?"
I said, "How hard could it be?"
他们在船上!
They're on the ship!
快上船!
Get to the ship!
无论你在干什么 我建议你加快速度 哥哥
Well, whatever you're doing, brother, I suggest you do it faster.
闭嘴 洛基
Shut up, Loki.
你肯定是漏了什么
You must have missed something.
我没有 每个按钮我都按过了
No, I didn't. I'm pressing every button on this thing.
不 别砸它 轻轻地按就好
No, don't hit it. Just press it gently.
我正在轻轻按呢 这不管用!
I'm pressing it gently, it's not working!
哈哈!
Ha, ha!
抓住他! 抓住他!
Get him! Get him!
- 你漏了根柱子没撞到  - 闭嘴!
- I think you missed a column. - Shut up!
听着 你为什么不让我开呢?
Look, why don't you let me take over?
我显然比你技术好多了
I'm clearly the better pilot.
真的? 我们两人中
Is that right? Well, out of the two of us,
究竟是谁真的会飞啊?
which one can actually fly?
天啊 她死了吗?
Oh, dear. Is she dead?
简
Jane.
我没事
I'm okay.
啊!
Ah!
不准说话
Not a word.
他们追上来了
Now they're following us.
他们朝我们开火了
Now they're firing at us.
多谢你的解说 洛基
Yeah, thank you for the commentary, Loki,
我一点儿也不觉得干扰!
it's not at all distracting!
真棒 你刚刚干掉了你爷爷
Well done. You just decapitated your grandfather.
这可真赞
You know, this is wonderful.
这主意真是太妙了
This is a tremendous idea.
让我们把全宇宙最大最显眼的船偷来
Let's steal the biggest, most obvious ship in the universe
再开着它逃跑
and escape in that.
绕着城市飞
Flying around the city,
看到什么撞什么 好让所有人都看见
smashing into everything in sight so everyone can see us.
太聪明了 索尔! 这真是太聪明了!
It's brilliant, Thor! It's truly brilliant!
看来地牢里的日子
I see your time in the dungeons
一点也没折损你的优雅 洛基
has made you no less graceful, Loki.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
真是令人惊讶
I'm impressed.
你开心就好
I'm glad you're pleased.
现在就按照你承诺的
Now, do as you promised.
带我们去你的秘密通道
And take us to your secret pathway.
- 范达尔  - 遵命
- Fandral.  - Right.
为阿斯加德效命
For Asgard.
对事不对人 兄弟们
Nothing personal, boys.
洛基...
Loki...
如果简单的话 别人就都会了
If it were easy, everyone would do it.
- 你疯了吗?  - 可能吧
- Are you mad?  - Possibly.
到啦!
Ta-da!
我们必须马上反击
We must strike now.
不
No.
阿斯加德毫无意义
Asgard is meaningless.
以太已经找到了回家的路
The Aether has found its way home.
我可以怎么利用那些流经血脉的能量?
What I could do with the power that flows through those veins?
它会将你消耗掉
It would consume you.
她熬过来了
She's holding up all right.
暂时而已
For now.
她强大到你无法置信
She's strong in ways you'd never even know.
告别吧
Say goodbye.
不是今天
Not this day.
今天 明天 一百年 全都一样
This day, the next, a hundred years, it's nothing.
她是凡人
It's a heartbeat.
你永远无法预知
You'll never be ready.
你珍视的挚爱女人
The only woman whose love you've prized
终有一天会被夺走
will be snatched from you.
那样你就满意了吗?
And will that satisfy you?
满足也不是我的天性
Satisfaction is not in my nature.
放弃也不是我的天性
Surrender is not in mine.
- 奥丁之子...  - 不
- The son of Odin...  - No.
不仅仅是奥丁的
Not just of Odin.
你以为你独享母亲的爱吗?
You think you alone were loved of Mother?
你习得了她的障眼法 但我得到了她的信任
You had her tricks, but I had her trust.
信任?
Trust?
这是她的遗言吗?
Was that her last expression?
你让她死的时候 她还信吗?
Trust? When you let her die?
- 你在监狱时 谁帮你的?  - 谁害我蹲监狱的?
- What help were you in your cell?  - Who put me there?
谁害的?
Who put me there?
你很清楚!
You know damn well!
你很清楚是谁!
You know damn well who!
她不会想我们自相残杀的
She wouldn't want us to fight.
自相残杀她也未必会惊讶
Well, she wouldn't exactly be shocked.
我也想信任你
I wish I could trust you.
那就信任我的愤怒吧
Trust my rage.
赛尔维格先生 请你签收你父亲的随身物品
You'll have to sign for your father's belongings, Mr. Selvig.
什么?
What?
哦 对
Oh, yeah.
我的父亲是艾瑞克・赛尔维格博士
My father, Dr. Erik Selvig.
一个棕色的男士皮钱包
One man's leather wallet, brown.
一个钥匙圈 三把钥匙
One key ring, three keys.
各式各样的...
Prescription medicine...
处方药
Various.
- 还有...  - 艾瑞克
- And...  - Erik.
- 这些玩意  - 对
- These.  - Yeah.
那些玩意
Those.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.
艾瑞克
Erik.
你好?
Yes?
我是黛西
It's, uh, Darcy.
黛西
Darcy.
见到你太好了
So good to see you.
我也想念你
Oh, I missed you, too.
你怎么找到我的?
How did you find me?
在电视上看到你裸奔了
You were naked on TV.
好吧 该走了 还有很多事要做
Okay, time to go, lots to do.
这样有点奇怪了
Getting weird now.
不该留下我来处理这样的破事
I should not be left in charge of stuff like this.
应该给我多点薪水 我大姨妈来了都没给我发薪
I don't get paid enough. I don't get paid, period.
顺便提下 我是伊安 是黛西的实习生
I'm Ian by the way, uh, Darcy's intern.
我也没薪水领
Yeah, I don't get paid either.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我脑袋中有个神
I've had a god in my brain.
我就不介绍它了
I don't recommend it.
赛尔维格博士 你的装置一直在哔哔响
Dr. Selvig, sir, your gear is beeping at me.
它经常这样 比我计算起来要快
It's happening. It's sooner than I calculated.
等等 发生什么事?
Wait. What's happening?
鸟吗?
Birds?
就因为鸟在飞吗?
Birds are happening?
是八哥 这是哀嚎
They're starlings. It's called a murmuration.
小时候我父亲经常带我去观鸟
My dad, he used to take me bird watching as a kid.
- 呆子  - 看!
- Nerd.  - Look!
它们去了哪儿?
Where did they go?
他妈的搞什么鬼?
What the hell was that?
为什么你还笑得出来?
Why are you smiling?
现在知道这个世界
There's nothing more reassuring
比你们更疯狂 我放心多了
than realizing that the world is crazier than you are.
带我去简的实验室
Take me to Jane's lab.
简 你醒了
Jane.
玛勒基斯
Malekith.
好的 你准备好了吗?
All right. Are you ready?
我准备好了
I am.
你这计划会让我们赔上性命
You know, this plan of yours is going to get us killed.
对 有可能
Yes, possibly.
你还不信任我吧 哥哥?
You still don't trust me, brother?
你会信任我吗?
Would you?
不 我不会
No, I wouldn't.
索尔!
Thor!
不要!
No!
你真的觉得我在乎芙蕾嘉吗?
You really think I cared about Frigga?
在乎你们任何一个人?
About any of you?
我想要一直是
All I ever wanted
让你和奥丁
was you and Odin
死在我脚下!
dead at my feet!
玛勒基斯!
Malekith!
我是冰巨人后裔洛基
I am Loki of Jotunheim,
给你带来了礼物
and I bring you a gift.
我要的回报只有一个...
I ask only one thing in return...
一个观赏阿斯加德
a good seat from which
燃为灰烬的好位子
to watch Asgard burn.
他是阿斯加德的敌人
He is an enemy of Asgard.
是他们地牢里的囚犯
He was a prisoner in their dungeons.
看着我
Look at me.
洛基! 动手!
Loki! Now!
啊!
Ah!
- 啊!  - 不要!
- Ah!  - No!
地狱见 怪物
See you in hell, monster.
不 不 不 不
No. No, no, no.
你这个笨蛋 不听我的
Oh, you fool, you didn't listen.
我知道...
I know...
我是个笨蛋 是个笨蛋
I'm a fool, I'm a fool.
坚持住 好吗?
Stay with me, okay?
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 对不起 对不起  - 嘘...
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.  - Shh...
没事的
It's okay.
It's all right.
我会告诉父王你今天做得很好
I'll tell Father what you did here today.
我不是为了他
I didn't do it for him.
不!
No!
他将会发动战争
He's going to unleash it.
不仅是对付阿斯加德或其它星球 玛勒基斯会毁掉一切
Not just on Asgard, or on a star. Malekith is going to destroy everything.
用什么方式?
How?
简 用什么方式?
Jane, how?
我看到他在地球上 为什么他会去地球?
I saw him on Earth. Why would he go to Earth?
天体汇聚
The Convergence.
天啊
Oh, God.
如果我不发现以太 所有这些事情就不会发生了
None of this would have happened if I hadn't found the Aether.
那样玛勒基斯会更快地
Then Malekith would've only possessed it
霸占太空
that much sooner.
我当时只是为了找到你
I only found it because I was looking for you.
简...
Jane...
现在我们被困在这里了
Now we're trapped here.
不是我的
It's not me.
喂?
Hello?
嗨 简 我是理查德
Hi, Jane, it's Richard.
理查德? 你在哪儿?
Richard? Where are you?
我还在办公室
I'm still at the office.
今天真是忙疯了
It's been a crazy day here today.
- 天啊 太好了  - 是吗?
- Oh, my God, this is amazing.  - Is it?
除了没有点东西吃
I quite enjoyed our lunch
我挺享受我们的午餐的
despite never actually ordering anything.
怎么这里会有信号?
How am I getting service here?
你不方便吗? 需要稍后再打给你吗?
Is this a bad time? Do you want me to try you later?
不 不 无论怎样 拜托不要挂电话
No, no, no. Please, whatever you do, do not hang up the phone.
那好吧
Okay, then.
不知道你是否想再一起出来
I was just wondering if you want to try again.
或者下次吃个晚饭
Uh, maybe dinner next time.
好 好 好
Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 不要挂电话 好吗?  - 好的
- Just stay on the phone, okay?  - Yeah, I will.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我打扰到你了吗?
Am I interrupting something?
不 不 不 没事
No, no, no. Nothing at all.
说吧
Come on.
我听不到你说话 你在隧道里面吗?
I'm losing you there. Are you in a tunnel?
我们要去哪儿?
Where are we going?
还在吗?
Hello?
为什么这里有那么多鞋子?
Why are there so many shoes in here?
还是发短信给她吧
I'll just text her.
谁是理查德?
So, who's Richard?
真的要问吗?
Really?
- 简!  - 嘿
- Jane!  - Hey.
你不能就那样跑掉的
You can't just leave like that.
整个世界都疯掉了
The whole world is going crazy.
我们发现的现象现在到处都是
All the stuff we saw is spreading.
- 你去参加化妆舞会了吗?  - 艾瑞克?
- Did you go to a party?  - Erik?
简! 太好了
Jane! How wonderful.
噢!
Oh!
- 你去了阿斯加德  - 你的裤子呢?
- You've been to Asgard.  - Where are your pants?
呃... 他说这样有助于思考
Oh, he, uh... He says it helps him think.
我需要你研究出来的所有资料
Okay, well, I'm going to need everything you got on this.
你一直在做的重量异常研究 所有东西
All the work you've been doing on gravimetric anomalies, everything.
好的
Okay.
你好吗 艾瑞克?
Are you well, Erik?
你弟弟没来吧?
Your brother's not coming, is he?
洛基死了
Loki is dead.
谢天谢地!
Oh, thank God!
我是说... 节哀顺变
I... I meant, I'm so sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
请原谅我 大人
Forgive me, my liege.
我从黑暗世界回来了 有消息禀告
I've returned from the Dark World with news.
索尔呢?
Thor?
那没有索尔或是武器的踪迹 不过...
There was no sign of Thor, or the weapon, but...
什么?
What?
我们发现了一具尸体
We found a body.
是洛基
Loki.
玛勒基斯打算在九界连为一线之时
Malekith is going to fire the Aether at a spot
启动以太元素
where all the nine worlds are connecting.
增强武器的冲击力
Amplifying the weapon's impact.
一旦发射到其它世界
Reach additional world,
能量就会成指数倍增加
the power will increase exponentially.
其毁灭效果是宇宙级的
The effect would be universal.
但九星连珠时间很短
But the Alignment is only temporary.
他必须在准确的时间到达准确的地点
He must be in exactly the right place at the right time.
我们怎么知道是哪里?
Well, how do we know where that is?
我们根据先人的指引
We follow the directions.
这种情况
This has happened before
在几千年前发生过 古人们都见证过
thousands of years ago, and the ancients were there to see it.
所有伟大的建筑
All the great constructions,
无论是玛雅人 中国人 还是埃及人造的
the Mayans, the Chinese, the Egyptians.
都利用了天体汇聚的重力效应
They made use of the gravitational effects of the Convergence.
而且还留下了地图
And they left us a map.
巨石阵
Stonehenge,
斯诺登峰
Snowdon,
大奥玛
the Great Orme.
这些坐标把我们指引到...
These are all coordinates taking us...
这里
Here.
格林尼治?
Greenwich?
九界之间的阻碍将几乎不存在
The walls between worlds will be almost non-existent.
将会产生极大的物理效应
Physics is going to go ballistic.
重力不停地增加衰减
Increases and decreases in gravity,
出现空间挤压现象
spatial extrusions.
现实世界被彻底摧毁
The very fabric of reality is going to be torn apart.
我去穿上裤子
I better get my pants.
认真点! 这很重要
Focus! This is important.
我们必须在驻地周围布置好它们
We have to hammer them in all around the site
这样简和艾瑞克就能从塔上启动了
and then Jane and Erik will activate them from the tower.
这是用胶带绑起来的
They're taped together.
你到底知不知道这些东西是干嘛用的?
Do you even know what these things do?
呃... 不知道
Uh... no.
我也不知道
Neither do I.
嘘!
Shh!
- 快点 快点 快点!  - 知道了
- Come on, come on, come on!  - Right.
我...
Holy...
靠
shit.
啊!
Ah!
你没必要大老远跑来 阿斯加德人
You needn't have come so far, Asgardian.
反正你也快死了
Death would've come to you soon enough.
那也不是被你杀死
Not by your hand.
你的世界从来就没有存在的意义
Your universe was never meant to be.
你的世界和你的家人
Your world and your family
将会被消灭!
will be extinguished!
我们快没时间了
We're running out of time.
- 快好了  - 你确定这样有用吗?
- Almost there.  - Are you sure this is going to work?
这些设备是用来监测异常现象的 而不是引起现象
These devices were made to detect anomalies, not cause them.
快点
Oh, come on.
快点 黛西
Come on, Darcy.
要知道 既然拥有了强大的能量
You know, with all that power,
你应该再加把劲儿
I thought you'd hit harder.
搞定
Done.
七分钟后 天体汇聚效应将达到最大值
The Convergence will be in full effect in seven minutes.
那意味着我们得让玛勒基斯至少忙活八分钟
That just means we have to keep Malekith busy for eight.
好的 你最好抱紧个什么东西
Okay, you might want to hold on to something.
真牛!
That is awesome!
你怎么做到的?
How did you do that?
呃 重力场可以
Well, the gravitational fields
和世界之间的弱分布点相互作用 产生...
interact with the weak spots between worlds, creating...
快搞定那个拿剑的家伙!
Ooh, get the guy with the sword!
- 完了  - 快走
- Oops.  - Let's go.
呃...
Um...
刚才到底什么情况?
What the hell just happened?
快跑!
Move!
你们都在这干什么呢?
What are you all doing?
得赶快离开这 快点!
You need to get out of here, now!
你开玩笑的 对吗?
You're joking, right?
索尔在外面呢
That's Thor out there.
他正在挥舞锤子打得风生水起!
He's waving his hammer around and everything!
啊!
Ah!
确认飞船是否属于敌方
Confirming ship is hostile.
已确认为敌舰
Confirmed, ship is hostile.
授权发射
You have permission to engage.
收到
Roger.
导弹锁定
Missiles locked.
发射
Missiles away.
导弹偏离目标
Missiles off target.
重复 偏离目标 战机失去控制
I repeat, target missed. I'm losing control.
求救! 求救! 完全失去控制
Mayday! Mayday! Lost positive control.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
信号连接不上了
My signal's not connecting.
简!
Jane!
快走
Come on.
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
你救了我
You saved my life.
是的
Yeah.
我想是的
I guess I did.
嗯
Mmm.
黛西?
Darcy?
简!
Jane!
- 伊安!  - 赛尔维格!
- Ian!  - Selvig!
快看!
Mew mew!
请小心站台缝隙
Mind the gap.
我怎么去格林尼治?
How do I get to Greenwich?
上车 三站就到
Take this train. Three stops.
请小心站台缝隙
Mind the gap.
抱歉 对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
- 我们没时间了  - 简
- We're out of time.  - Jane.
简!
Jane!
索尔!
Thor!
太晚了
We're too late.
天体汇聚效应已达到峰值
The Convergence is at its peak.
这东西能阻止他吗?
Can those things stop him?
在这儿可不行
Not from here.
我们无法接近他
We can't get close enough.
我可以
I can.
玛勒基斯!
Malekith!
黑暗归来 阿斯加德人
Darkness returns, Asgardian.
你是来见证你们世界的末日的吗?
Have you come to witness the end of your universe?
我来接受你的投降
I've come to accept your surrender.
你觉得自己能阻止我?
You think you can stop this?
以太是无敌的
The Aether cannot be destroyed.
但你不是
But you can.
索尔! 不
Thor! No.
简!
Jane!
啊!
Ah!
大家都没事吧?
Everybody okay?
他会回来的
He's gonna come back.
只不过 要知道
Except, you know,
他上次一走就差不多两年
last time he was gone for, like, two years.
现在只过了两天 所以...
Well, it's only been two days, so...
他走前说什么了吗?
Did he say anything before he left?
说了 他说他要和他老爸处理一些事情
Yeah, he had to figure some stuff out with his father.
他救我出来的时候... 犯了什么叛国罪
He kinda committed treason... on our way out.
哦
Oh.
你曾说过没有比我更加英明的君主
You once said there would never be a wiser king than me.
你错了
You were wrong.
九星连珠将九界团结到了一起
The Alignment has brought all the realms together.
所有人都看到你为了拯救他们而视死如归
Every one of them saw you offer your life to save them.
阿斯加德应该给予你什么报答呢?
What can Asgard offer its new king in return?
自由地生活
My life.
父王 我不能做阿斯加德之主
Father, I cannot be king of Asgard.
我会为阿斯加德和九界战斗到死
I will protect Asgard and all the realms with my last and every breath,
但在王位上 我却做不到
but I cannot do so from that chair.
洛基过去胡作非为 但他懂我永远也学不会的治国方略
Loki, for all his grave imbalance, understood rule as I know I never will.
残忍 牺牲...
The brutality, the sacrifice...
这些改变了你
it changes you.
我宁愿做一个好人 也不想当一个圣君
I'd rather be a good man than a great king.
这是你自己决定的 还是你的爱人希望的?
Is this my son I hear, or the woman he loves?
当你说话的时候 我又何尝没看到母后的影子?
When you speak, do I never hear Mother's voice?
这不是为了简 父王
This is not for Jane, Father.
她并不知道我来这说了什么
She does not know what I came here to say.
现在 无论是阻止我见她 还是说她左右了我的选择
Now, forbid me to see her, or say she can rule at my side.
都于事无补
It changes nothing.
一个儿子渴望王位
One son who wanted the throne too much,
另一个却避之不及
another who will not take it.
这就是我的结局?
Is this my legacy?
洛基死得很光荣
Loki died with honor.
而我会活得像他一样光荣
I shall try to live the same.
这样的结局还不够好吗?
Is that not legacy enough?
如果你配得上它
It belongs to you.
就归你了
If you are worthy of it.
我会努力的
I shall try to be.
我不会为你祷告 也不会为你祈福
I cannot give you my blessing, nor can I wish you good fortune.
我知道
I know.
即使我将来真的以你为荣
If I were proud of the man my son had become,
我也不会说出来
even that, I could not say.
只会深藏心里
It would speak only from my heart.
去吧
Go,
我的孩子
my son.
谢谢你 父王
Thank you, Father.
不
No.
我得谢谢你
Thank you.
不要走开 精彩稍后继续
我来向你们介绍
I present to you,
这位是"收集者"坦利亚・蒂万
Taneleer Tivan, the Collector.
喔...
Whoa...
是阿斯加德人 荣幸之至
Asgardians, it's an honor.
你知道我们为何而来
You know why we're here.
当然
Of course.
但请容我一问
But, if I may ask,
为什么不把它保存在阿斯加德里?
why not keep it secure in your own vault?
宇宙魔方已经在阿斯加德了
The Tesseract is already on Asgard.
把两块拥有超强能量的石头放在一起很不明智
It is not wise to keep two Infinity Stones so close together.
确实
That's very wise.
我可以向你保证
I can assure you,
把它放在我的收藏里
it will be absolutely safe here,
会非常安全
in my collection.
最好如此
See that it is.
拿到一个
One down.
还有五个
Five to go.